

Mojib Mohammad

Date of birth: 01/01/1990 | **Nationality:** Afghan | **Gender** Male | (+1) 5103592953 |

mmohammad3@outlook.com | https://mojibmohammad.netlify.app/ |

https://www.linkedin.com/in/mojib-mohammad/ | Other: https://github.com/mojib2014 |

1209 52nd Ave, 94601, Oakland, United States

About me: Experienced full stack software/web developer with a demonstrated history of working in the computer software industry. Skilled in solving problems, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Java, React, React Native, Node.js, SQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Firebase, Git, Gihub, Heroku, Mocha, Chai, Jest and Management. I have absolutely no trouble moving fast and breaking things.

WORK EXPERIENCE

08/21/2019 - CURRENT - San Francisco

HEALTH CARE SECURITY OFFICER - SECURITAS

Customer Service, protect people, property, information, and reputation. Respond Rapidly to security emergencies within the health care setting.

02/01/2016 - 08/25/2019 - San Francisco, United States

UBER DRIVER - UBER INC

Safe driving, communication, time management, and customer service.

12/31/2016 - 04/08/2017 - Fremont, United States

PRODUCTION ASSOCIATE - TESLA MOTORS

Perform standardized work process and following defined work instructions and sequences at a defined pace, repetitively for an extended period of time, and rotating as required. Operate robotic system and complex manufacturing equipment for process processes under supervision.

05/03/2010 - 02/22/2014 - Kabul, Afghanistan

TRANSLATOR & CULTURAL ADVISOR - US ARMY

Worked as interpreter/translator with US Armed forces in Afghanistan.

Assisted US Military in training/mentoring mission for Afghan National Army and Afghan National Police. Translated different documents into native languages.

04/30/2018 - CURRENT

FREELACE - FREELANCER

Implement and document web-accessible software based on the designs provided.

Align the client's web presence with its bussines strategy, troubleshoot software problems and issues and look for ways to improve the application.

PERSONAL PROJECT

Coders Corner: Asimple application for improving coding(software development) Skills(for students and mentors).

Technologies uesed: JavaScript | HTML5 | CSS3 | jQuery | MDN API | Anime.js | AJAX

Project Link: https://putincake.github.io/Coders-Corner/ Github Link: https://putincake.github.io/Coders-Corner/

PERSONAL PROJECT

Dent soft: Dent Soft (DS) is a streamlined and standardized electronic system specially designed for multiple users in dental clinics.

Technologies Used: React.js | MongoDB | Node.js | Dropzone/Cloudinary | Google Authentication | Reactstrap

Project Link: https://dent-soft.herokuapp.com/

Github Link: https://github.com/mojib2014/dent-soft

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

12/31/2004 – 03/07/2010 – Kabul , Afghanistan **BACHELOR (MEDICINE) –** Ghazanfar Institute of Health&Science

Field(s) of study

Medicine

JAVASCRIPT CERTIFIED DEVELOPER - w3chools

https://www.w3schools.com

11/01/2020

THE ULTIMATE DATA STRUCTURES & ALGORITHMS - Code With Mosh

https://codewithmosh.com

11/28/2020 - CURRENT Online

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT - Codecademy

Field(s) of study

Information and Communication Technologies

https://www.codecademy.com

05/13/2018 - 07/13/2018

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT - UC Berkeley Extension

Field(s) of study

Full Stack

https://extension.berkeley.edu

02/2020

THE COMPLETE NODE.JS COURSE - Code With Mosh

https://codewithmosh.com

01/2020

MASTERING REACT - Code With Mosh

https://codewithmosh.com

01/2019

OBJECT ORIENTED PROGRAMMING IN JAVASCRIPT. - Code With Mosh

https://codewithmosh.com

01/2019

THE ULTIMATE JAVASCRIPT MASTERY - Code With Mosh

https://codewithmosh.com

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): PASHTO/DARI

Other language(s):

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production	Spoken interaction	
ENGLISH	C2	C2	C2	C2	C2
SPANISH	C1	C1	C1	C1	C1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

DIGITAL SKILLS

Microsoft Office | Bootstrap | Linux | Deployment tool: Heroku | Management | problems solving

Front End

JavaScript | Testing with Jest | HTML 5 | CSS3 | Bootstrap 4 | React/Redux | Versioning: Git, Github

Back End

Mocha + Chai | NodeJS and ExpressJs | Microservice archiceture, REST API, GraphQI | RESTful api | MySQL & PostgreSQL | MongoDB Query Language | Object-Oriented Programming | Firebase (Functions, Auth, Firestore, Storage)